Queen's Chapel Civic Association Records 105
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Queen's Chapel Civic Association Records
1965-1995
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Queen's Chapel Civic Association
105
1.5 Linear feet
3 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Organizational Information This series contains the Queen's Chapel Civic Association's constitution and bylaws, corporate reports, administrative materials, newsletters, meeting minutes, and correspondence. Series 2: Community Issues This series includes correspondence, announcements, and publications concerning community issues such as crime, traffic and transportation, public works, education, and elections. Series 3: Civic Organizations This series contains information and publications from other local civic and community organizations.
Biographical / Historical
On September 14, 1965, the Brookland Civic Association ceded the area bounded by Sargent Road NE, Eastern Avenue NE, Michigan Avenue NE and South Dakota Avenue NE to the newly formed Queen's Chapel Civic Association. The group's goal was to "work for the betterment of [the] area and the community at large in the following ways: presentation of informative speakers; publication of the 'Civic Seer;' [and] maintaining close relationships with the 5th District, the D.C. Federation of Civic Associations, and with schools."
Custodial History
The collection was donated in 1996, by Richard Teasley, President of the Queen's Chapel Civic Association, and Ophelia C. Daniel, a former officer.
Custodial History
This collection was donated to the Library in 1996 by Richard Teasley, President of the Queen's Chapel Civic Association, and Ophelia C. Daniel, a former officer.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of meeting minutes, administrative materials, community newsletters and announcements, correspondence, and legal documents related to the Queen's Chapel Civic Association.
Neighborhoods; Associations, institutions, etc; Organizational Records; Legal documents; Correspondence; Community organization; Lamond Riggs, (Washington, D.C.)
- Series 1: Organizational Information
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the organization's constitution and bylaws, corporate reports, administrative materials, newsletters, meeting minutes, and correspondence.
  - Constitution/By-Laws/Corporate Reports, 1965-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Budgets and Reports, 1969-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Materials, 1977-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Trips and Outings, 1967-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Announcements, 1967-1977, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Retirement Party for Mr. Dulaney - Postman, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Civic Seer Newsletter, 1966-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Civic Seer Newsletter, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Civic Seer Newsletter, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Civic Seer Newsletter, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1968-1970, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Vice President Teasley, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Rev. David Turner, 1989-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Officers and Block Captains, 1967-1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971-1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series 2: Community Issues
  This series includes correspondence, announcements and publications concerning community issues such as crime, traffic and transportation, public works, education, and elections.
  - Fort Lincoln, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Crime, 1968-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Public Works, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - CandP Telephone Co., 1985-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - PEPCO, 1979-1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Traffic and Transportation, 1967-1968, 1975, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Pollution, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Elections, 1968-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Education, 1969-1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Capital Improvement Program, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Public Hearings, 1971, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Zoning, 1973-1974, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Cancer, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Events, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - People's Counsel, 1990, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Series 3: Civic Organizations
  This series contains information and publications from other local civic and community organizations.
  - Civic Organizations, 1977, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - DC Federation of Civic Organizations, 1969-1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Advisory Neighborhood Commission 5A, 1975-1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Advisory Neighborhood Commission 5B, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ward 5, 1987, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Service Area 2, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - AARP Brookland Woodbridge Chapter, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Metro Women's Democratic Club, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Upper Northeast News, 1969, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Northeast Washington Star, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - DC Government, 1967-1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)